"旺达幻视"前情提要...
Previously on WandaVision...
才艺表演筹款是这一季最重要的活动
The town show fundraiser is the most important event of the season
我希望我们能融入
and I want us to fit in.
我不知道我来这儿干什么
I don't know what I'm doing here.
-我是旺达  -杰拉尔丁
-I'm Wanda. -Geraldine.
旺达 能听到吗
Wanda, can you read me?
刚刚多蒂很奇怪
Something strange happened with Dottie.
那之前也很奇怪 有点难解释
Well, something strange happened before that, too. It's hard to explain.
看来要融入也不难
It wasn't so hard to fit in after all.
那是什么
What is that?
不
No.
-这是真的吗  -是亲爱的
-Is this really happening? -Yes, my love.
♪ 旺达幻视 ♪
WandaVision
♪ 我们做了点吃的 ♪
We got something cooking
♪ 看起来味道不错 ♪
And it's looking good
主演
旺达·马克西莫夫
♪ 吃的已经做好了 ♪
We've got something cooking
♪ 谁知道我们会做呢 ♪
And who knew we could
幻视
♪ 美好的期望 总会带来麻烦 ♪
All great expectations Lead to complications
♪ 但也有许多乐趣 ♪
But it's groovy and fun
♪ 只要我和你 ♪
It's me and it's you
♪ 在一起 一加一 ♪
Together, one plus one
♪ 就能大于二 ♪
Is more than two
♪ 旺达幻视 ♪
WandaVision
♪ 各种意外之喜 ♪
Some sudden surprises
♪ 纷至沓来 ♪
Come in all shapes and sizes
♪ 就像彩虹和阳光 ♪
But it's rainbows and sun
♪ 你和我 ♪
It's you and it's me
♪ 在一起 一加一就是一家人 ♪
Together, one plus one is family
旺达幻视
第一季 第３集 彩色版
♪ 旺达幻视 ♪
WandaVision
是的 确实怀孕了
Yep! Definitely pregnant.
这我们已经知道了
Well, that much we figured.
只是有点意外
It's just kinda taken us by surprise.
来得有些突然 太突然了
It's just kinda suddenly. Quite suddenly, wasn't it?
可以说一夜之间就...
I mean, practically overnight. I mean...
这是怎么回事
How did this happen?
是这样 男人和女人
You see, when a man and a woman
彼此深爱...
love each other very much...
[pink和blue也可指代女孩和男孩]
我们是高兴极了
Well, we're just tickled pink, or blue.
这差不多有四个月了吧
You're at about four months now. Is that right?
我想也是
I thought as much.
我们常让孕妈用水果来观察孩子的大小
We let the little ladies keep tabs on their growing babies with fruit.
比较容易理解
Makes it simple for them.
四个月时 胎儿和梨子一般大
At four months, the fetus is about as big as a pear.
五个月像木瓜 六个月像葡萄柚
At five months, a papaya. Six, grapefruit.
七个月像菠萝 八个月蜜瓜
Seven, pineapple. Eight, honeydew.
只是假设
Hypothetically speaking,
12小时的胎儿 像什么水果呢
what size fruit would it be at, say, 12 hours?
什么 12小时
Pardon? 12 hours?
这个问题没有意义[没有水果]
Well, I think this line of questioning is fruitless.
如果这样 我们需要担心吗
Well, hypothetically speaking, should we be concerned?
如果这样准爸爸都会焦虑的
Hypothetically speaking, every new father-to-be gets nervous.
我可是铁打的神经 所以医生 你的理论...
Well, I have nerves of steel, so there goes your theory, Mr. Doctor...
幻视 去送送医生吧
Vision, why don't you see the doctor out?
好主意 行
Good idea. Yes.
非常感谢您专门跑一趟 尼尔森医生
Thank you so much for dropping by, Dr. Nielson.
幸好你们来得及时
Well, I'm just glad you caught me in time.
下午我就要带老婆去度假了
I'm taking the wife on vacation this afternoon.
度假愉快 赫伯
Have a nice holiday! Herb!
兄弟
Buddy!
旺达的事 能不能替我们保密...
Listen, you can keep the news of Wanda's...
你知我知就行
You know, just between us because,
因为事情发生得太快了
I don't know, everything's happening so quickly.
我们希望这消息只有家里人知道
We'd like to keep the news just in the family for right now.
当然 我谁都不说
Of course. Mum's the word.
出发 去百慕大
I'm off. Bermuda, baby!
去吧
Yes.
赫伯
Herb!
你这树篱修剪机
Think you might've taken the hedge-trimming
伸得有点远了 朋友
a little too far there, old chum.
是啊
So, I have.
谢了 兄弟
Thanks, buddy.
不客气
Yeah. Don't mention it.
刚刚外面好奇怪...
Strangest thing just happened outside with...
我的天 又大了
Nelly! Have you gotten bigger?
是吗 这个角度我看不出来
Have I? I can't tell from this angle.
我等不及...
I can't wait...
看到骄傲的木瓜了
to be a proud papaya.
"筑巢反应 想要打扫 收拾家里的强烈冲动
"Nesting, the overwhelming urge during pregnancy to clean,
想要为新生儿做好准备"
organize, and prepare the home for the new baby."
看 你都成专家了 没什么好担心的
See? You're an expert already. We've got nothing to worry about.
只需要担心孕妇晨吐
Nothing to worry about outside of morning sickness,
情绪波动 背痛和...
mood swings, aching back and...
脚痛 亲爱的 你坐会儿吧
Feet. Darling, you should probably sit down.
别傻了 我的感觉只有激动 高兴 还有...
Don't be silly. All I feel is excitement, happiness, and...
已经开始踢你了吗
Kicking? Already?
这感觉真奇怪
It's such a strange sensation.
像它在扑棱翅膀
It's kind of fluttery.
是我做的吗 我没想做来着
Did I do that? I didn't mean to.
亲爱的...
Darling..
你好 小家伙
Hello, little fella.
如果是第一次踢你
Well, if that was the first kick,
那相当于你已经怀孕六个月了
that puts you at about six months!
我以为我速度够快了呢
Boy, boy, I thought I had super speed.
我都追不上你呀 不要误会
I can't keep up. Please don't misinterpret.
我等不及要见到你了 小比利
I can't wait to meet you, little Billy.
-比利  -是呀
-Billy? -Yeah.
我觉得应该叫汤米
Well, I was thinking Tommy.
经典的美国名字
Just a nice, classic, all-American name.
汤米 也是 比利也不错吧
Tommy. Yeah. Yeah. Then there's Billy, isn't there?
跟威廉·莎士比亚同名
Named after William Shakespeare.
"世间如舞台 芸芸众生 粉墨登场"
"All the world's a stage. All the men and women, merely players."
要结束争论只有一种办法
Well, I guess there's only one solution to this debate.
希望是个女孩
Hope for a girl.
得快点决定了
Well, we ought to decide soon.
据我估算 预产期...
I estimate the baby's due...
不是线性发展的 可能是对数函数
It's not a constant progression, assumingly logarithmic,
如果画出胎儿目前的发育过程曲线...
but were I to graph the fetal development thus far...
不等你算出来 他就该出生了
He's gonna be here before you figure it out.
-最接近的结论是比利…  -汤米
-Nearest I can conclude is that Billy... -Tommy.
周五下午出生
Is due Friday afternoon.
三天后
In three days?
我是该坐会儿了
Maybe I should sit down.
我们说好了吧
I think we have an understanding.
开始计时
Start the clock.
结束
Time.
-你的最佳纪录  -太棒了
-Your personal best. -Yes!
必须得做好准备
We are nothing if not prepared.
亲爱的
Darling?
书里提过这个吗
Do any of your books talk about this?
不疼 但感觉很奇怪
It's not painful, but it's strange.
-收紧的感觉吗  -对没错
-A tightening sensation? -Yep, that's it.
有 在哪里 第几页
Yes. Where was it, where was it?
"布拉克斯顿·希克斯宫缩 又称假性临产
"Braxton Hicks contractions, also known as false labor,
通常开始于妊娠晚期
usually starts in the third trimester.
1875年以约翰·布拉克斯顿·希克斯命名"
Named after John Braxton Hicks in 1875."
宝贝
Honey.
对不起 太好了
Sorry. Yes. Yes. Excellent!
我们可以一起做个呼吸练习
Gives us a chance to work on our breathing exercises.
像这样
It should go like this.
没什么用 我还是能感觉到
Yeah, it's not working. I can still feel it.
我的错
I'm sorry.
-怎么回事  -什么情况
-What's happening now?  -What the... What the Dickens?
别管厨房了
Let's abandon the kitchen.
停下了
It stopped.
是
Yes.
我去看看邻居们
I'll go check on the neighbors.
好
Yes.
菲尔
Phil?
这副耳环会显胖吗
Do these earrings make me look fat?
谢天谢地
Thank God.
看来整条街都停电了
It appears that the whole block is out.
这还只是假宫缩
And that was just a fake contraction.
谁知道真的宫缩会是什么样子
Who knows what will happen when the real thing starts.
你说他们会不会知道是因为我
Do you think they know it's my fault?
邻居吗
Our neighbors?
是啊 那么多次千钧一发
Well, yes, with all the close calls we've been having,
韦斯特维的人 好像总是差点就要发现我们的秘密
it seems the people of Westview are always on the verge of discovering our secret.
我懂你的意思
Yes, I know what you mean.
而且不仅如此
But it's more than that, isn't it?
和哈特夫妇吃的晚餐
Mr. and Mrs. Hart, dinner.
赫伯在外面的反常行为
Outside with Herb.
我觉得这里有点不对劲 旺达
I think something's wrong here, Wanda.
我懂你的意思
Yes, I know what you mean.
其实 我们是在未知的处境
The truth is, we are in unchartered waters
你知道吗
and you know what?
我也很担心
I'm anxious, too.
我们只是不知道未来会如何
We just don't know what to expect.
是啊
Nope.
孩子会是人类还是机器
Will the baby be human or Synthezoid?
或者是混血
A bit of both?
只要像妈妈 比利就很完美
If he's anything like his ma, Billy will be perfect.
你是说汤米
You mean Tommy.
亲爱的 你没事吧
No, darling, are you all right?
-这次是真的  -什么
-This is a real one! -What?
你不是说周五下午吗
I thought you said Friday afternoon!
我没想到发育曲线
Well, I didn't consider that the timings
基准点之间的时间会这么随机
between developmental benchmarks could be quite random!
好多了
Better.
是 亲爱的 谢谢你 过去了
Yes, darling, thank you, it's passing.
小幻...
Vis...
怎么了
Yes, dear?
我羊水好像破了
I think my water just broke.
没错 宝贝
Yes, dear.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no!
对不起 妈妈...
Sorry, Mom...
你需要放松一下吗
Do you need a break?
你太懂我了
You read my mind.
跟我来
Come with me.
逃往完全属于自己的世界
Escape to a world all your own,
让烦恼随风而逝
where your problems float away.
当你想逃离 又哪儿都不想去
When you wanna get away, but you don't wanna go anywhere.
九头蛇浴粉 做家中女神
Hydra Soak, find the goddess within.
九头蛇沐浴 高级浴粉
九头蛇沐浴高级浴粉
我刚刚在书上看到水中分娩的好处
Well, I was just reading about the advantages of water birth.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness.
我帮你 亲爱的 好了
Let me help you up, dear. There you go.
真是一团糟
What a mess.
好多了
That's better.
亲爱的 你说是不是该...
Darling, do you think it's time to...
-给医生打电话  -没错
-Call the doctor? -Yeah.
我同意
Yes, I do, dear.
糟了 电话也坏了
Damn, the phones are down, too.
我跑过去
I better run.
不过 他可能已经去度假了
Except, he might have already left for vacation.
去哪儿 这种时候去
Where? At a time like this?
说句公道话 宝宝大概提前了九个月出生
Well, in fairness, darling, the baby is approximately nine months early.
我走了
I better leg it.
你在这儿可以吗
You'll be all right here?
好吧
Okay.
糟了
Shoot.
旺达 你好
Wanda, what's up?
今天有24度呢
It's 75 degrees out.
你这是什么时尚吗
You're making a fashion statement?
杰拉尔丁 这个时间不太对[你来得不是时候]
Geraldine. You know, now is not really a good time.
不 不 很性感
No, no, no, it's foxy.
有机会借我穿穿
You'll have to let me borrow it sometime.
但这次我是来借个桶
But first, I gotta borrow a bucket.
不是穿 是用
Not to wear, to use.
我们家天花板上的管子
Somehow, all the pipes in my ceiling
莫名其妙都爆了 我赶紧跑出来
burst at once and I gotta bail myself out.
当然 没问题
All right, sure.
你在这儿等着
Just stay right there.
我记得厨房有个桶
I think I might have a bucket in the kitchen.
那好吧
Okay, then.
应该就在水池下面
I think it's just here under the sink!
你没事吧
Are you all right in there?
没事 我正在找
Yes, I am just looking.
我来帮你
I'll come help.
别 别这么客气
No! I mean, no thank you.
找到了
Bingo.
你看看你
Would you look at that?
什么
What?
水果 旺达 谢谢你
Fruit. Wanda! Thank you.
肯定很美味
Yummy.
希望你的管子早点修好
Well, good luck with the leak.
说到这... 旺达 我有个问题要问你
That... Say, Wanda, I've got a question for you.
你知道我一直在做那个临时工吧
You know how I've been working that temp job, right?
我老板哈德克斯 昨天像疯了一样...
Well, my boss, Mr. Haddox, he was going crazy yesterday...
你瞧我 话太多了 你应该有事要忙吧
Look at me going on and on like you got all the time in the world.
-我先走了…  -等下别走
-Let me go on and get out... -Wait. No.
-给我讲讲那个临时工作  -这才对嘛
-Tell me about the temp job. -That's my girl.
昨天 我老板哈德克斯
So, yesterday my boss, Mr. Haddox,
像疯了一样 要给早餐麦片想标语
was going crazy working on the slogan for a new breakfast cereal.
你知道那个有棉花糖月球人的麦片吧
You know, the one with the little marshmallow Moonmen?
对 对 就是那个
Yeah, yeah, yeah, those.
离展示还有10分钟
So, it's 10 minutes before the big presentation,
他什么都没想出来
and Mr. Haddox has got nothin'.
只是不停地打嗝 我从没见过有人那样打嗝
Nothin', that is, except the worst case of hiccups I ever did see.
旺达 他一个字都说不出来
Wanda. He couldn't get out one word,
更别说想广告词了
let alone a whole pitch.
我想了各种办法想帮他
So I'm tryin' every trick in the book to help this poor man.
比如藏在柜子后面
I'm hidin' behind filing cabinets
趁他不注意跳出来吓他 像这样
and jumpin' out when he least expects it, like!
旺达
Wanda.
什么声音
What was that?
-你听到了吗  -没
-Did you hear that? -No.
好像什么东西在叫 就像...
It was like a chattering sound, like...
就像...
Like a...
对
Yeah.
那是我新买的冰箱嵌入式制冰机
That's my new ice maker built right into the fridge.
真精致 话说回来
You're fancy. So now, at this point,
我帮哈德克斯先生倒立在饮水机前面
I am helping Mr. Haddox do a handstand under the water cooler...
试试看
because, you know, why not try
头朝下 能不能止嗝
a little upside down, drink those hiccups away.
谁知道 就在那时 客户进来了
And wouldn't you know it, in that moment, in walks the client.
不
No.
没错 但你了解我 旺达
Yes. Yes. But you know me, Wanda,
无论发生什么 我都能保持冷静
I keeps my cool, no matter what's goin' down.
我看看客户
I look at the client,
再看看哈德克斯先生悬空的脚
and I look at Mr. Haddox's feet floating in the air next to me,
又回头看看客户 然后说
and I look back at the client, and I say,
"引力牌麦片 助你开启全新的一天"
"Gravity Os, launch into your day, the right way."
谢天谢地
Thank you.
哈德克斯先生昨天也是这么说的
Yes, and that's exactly what Mr. Haddox said
然后他让我去收拾东西
right before he told me to clean out my desk.
不 杰拉尔丁
No, Geraldine.
他不会开除你了吧
He didn't fire you.
亲爱的
Sugar.
他雇了我
He hired me.
旺达 我升职了
Wanda! I landed a promotion.
现在我要上班了 就需要一些办公用品
And now that I've gone all corporate, I need some office supplies.
所以才想问
Which brings me to my question.
那些东西你还留着吗
Do y'all still keep those in your spare room?
希望你不会介意
Because I was hoping you wouldn't mind
-跟你的好朋友分享  -等等
-sharing with your good friend. -Wait. Wait.
这不会是真的吧
Is that what I think it is?
一只鹳 对 听我解释
A stork, yes, I can explain.
不 是婴儿床
No! The crib.
要出生了 宝宝要出生了
It's coming. The baby's coming.
你怀孕了
You're pregnant?
百慕大在召唤我 这破车
Bermuda awaits and my car
却在这时候抛锚了
decides to poop out right at this moment.
幻视先生 怎么了 夫人一切都好吗
Mr. Vision? What, is everything okay with the wife?
只要跑得快 就不会有事
Yes. So long as we hurry.
斯坦
But, Stan!
说好要给我买新套装的呢
What about my brand-new two-piece?
旺达
Okay, Wanda.
得让你舒服点 好吗
Now, let's get you comfortable. Okay?
我就在这儿躺一下
I think I'm gonna lay down right here.
-好  -幻视去找医生了
-Okay. -Vision ran to get the doctor.
马上就回来
He'll be back soon.
不 没时间了
No, no, there's not enough time for that.
放松 放松
Relax. Relax.
你知道怎么呼吸吧
You know your breathing, right?
旺达 我听不到
Wanda, I can't hear you.
可能是我消息滞后了
I may be late to the party,
但我相信这些应该会有个合理的解释
but I imagine there is a logical explanation for this.
都是自然发生的事
It's all perfectly natural!
你做得很好
You're doing great.
非常棒 看着我 看着我
You're doing great. Look at me. Look at me.
加油
Come on.
我做不到
I can't do this.
你可以
Yes, you can.
我不行 我不行
I can't. I can't.
你可以
You can do this.
你可以 一定可以的
Yes, you can. You can do this.
该使劲了
It's time to start pushing.
准备好了吗 准备好了
You ready? You're ready. You're ready.
用力 用力 旺达 用力
Push. Push, Wanda. Push!
用力 非常棒
Push! That a girl.
是个男孩
It's a boy.
真漂亮
He's perfect.
不 我没赶上
No. I missed it.
医生 能来厨房帮帮我吗
Doc, why don't you help me out in the kitchen there?
速度太快了 像飞一样
We went so fast, it was like we were flying.
你真棒 旺达
Well done, Wanda.
你不想让儿子看看你的真面目吗
Well, don't you wanna meet your son as yourself?
你真厉害
You're strong.
你好 小汤米
Hello there, little Tommy.
汤米
Tommy?
对 汤米
Yes, Tommy.
什么
What?
我的天
Good heavens!
还有个宝宝
There's another baby coming.
比利
Billy?
旺达 用力 用力
Wanda, push! Push!
一根指头都不少
Twenty fingers and 20 toes.
健健康康的两个儿子
You've got two healthy baby boys on your hands.
谢谢你 医生
Thank you, Doctor.
这是我的职责
All in a day's work.
谢谢你帮忙 小姐
And thank you for your assistance, young lady.
我觉得你很适合当护士
I think you might have what it takes to be a nurse.
我送你出去 医生
Allow me to walk you out, Doctor.
好的 这次走慢点
All right. As long as we actually walk this time.
来
Come.
太感谢你了
I do owe you a debt of gratitude.
尼尔森医生
Well, Dr. Nielson,
希望不会耽误你们旅行
I hope you're still able to make your trip.
旅行
Yes, my trip.
我们可能去不成了
I don't think we'll get away after all.
毕竟 小镇 很难...
Small towns, you know. So hard to...
逃脱
Escape.
-她在那儿做什么  -不知道
-What is she doing in there? -I don't know.
-你们好  -你好
-Howdy, neighbours! -Howdy!
你看见她进去了吗
Did you see her go inside?
她进去了
She went right in.
-她的肚子…  -杰拉尔丁…
-And her tummy was... -Did Geraldine...
今天很难忘 对吧
Remarkable day we're having, no?
你们也停电了吗
Did you lose power, too?
对
Sure did.
不过也挺好的 拉尔夫在暗处更好看
But Ralph looks better in the dark, so I'm not complaining.
赫伯
Herb.
兄弟
Buddy.
好的
Okay.
我回去找旺达了
Well, I'll get back to Wanda.
幻视
Vision.
杰拉尔丁在陪旺达吗
Is Geraldine inside with Wanda?
对 怎么了
Yes. Why?
你真坚强
You're such a strong lady.
你能相信吗 是双胞胎
Can you believe it? Twins!
我也是双胞胎
I'm a twin.
我有个哥哥
I had a brother.
叫皮特罗
His name was Pietro.
是奥创杀了他吧
He was killed by Ultron, wasn't he?
你说什么
What did you say?
她刚来镇上 谁都不熟
She's new to town. Brand-new.
没有亲人
There's no family.
没有丈夫
No husband.
这也没什么问题
Well, there's nothing wrong with that.
没有家
No home.
什么
What?
你刚说什么
What did you say just now?
我说 旺达
I said, Wanda,
你真坚强
you're such a strong lady.
还要我再说一次吗
Should I say it one more time for good measure?
不
No.
你刚才说皮特罗怎么了
What did you say about Pietro?
皮特罗
Pietro?
我帮你哄孩子吧
I'll take a shift rocking the babies.
不 你该走了
No, I think you should leave.
旺达 别这样
Wanda, don't be like that.
你什么意思 她没有家
What do you mean, she has no home?
她来这儿是因为...
She came here because...
她来这儿 是因为我们都...
She came here because we're all...
是因为我们都怎么了
She came here because we're all what?
你想说什么
What're you trying to tell me?
-那是什么  -什么
-What is that? -What?
那个
That.
那个符号
That symbol.
我 我...
I, I...
你是谁
Who are you?
我不...
I don't...
她来这儿 是因为我们都...
She came here because we're all...
别说了
Stop it!
你是谁
Who are you?
旺达...
Wanda...
我...
I...
旺达
Wanda.
我先走了
Well, I better get going.
我要去编绳结了
That macramé's not gonna hitch itself.
赫伯
Herb?
回见 幻视
Catch you on the flip side, Vision.
旺达
Wanda?
杰拉尔丁呢
Where's Geraldine?
她走了 亲爱的 她要赶回家
She left, honey. She had to rush home.
欢迎来到韦斯特维